Bye-bye!
バイバイ　また明日ね
See you tomorrow.
はい
Hello?
え　今すぐ？
What? Right now?
It's not impossible, but...
別に無理じゃないけど
What? Shun-chan's speaking so casually!
ガビーン　春ちゃんがタメ口で喋ってる
Fine. I'll bring it.
Who cares if he does?
いいじゃねぇか　タメ口でも
うん　じゃね
Okay, see you then.
What's going on, Shun?
どうしたの　春
It's just that Fuyuki and I mixed up our English notebooks.
あ　いいえ　冬樹と僕の英語ノートが逆になってたんですけど
今日こそノート提出しないと大変だから
He said he'll be in big trouble if he doesn't turn his in today,
so he asked me to bring it to him at school.
学校まで持ってきてって
あら
Oh, dear.
Who's Fuyuki?
冬樹って？
My younger brother.
He's a second year in middle school.
あ　弟です　中学二年の
Younger brother?
弟　春ちゃん弟いんの？！
Shun-chan, you have a younger brother?
あ　あと上に姉が二人いるんですけど
I have two older sisters, too...
What? I totally thought your family was all women...
えーー　俺絶対女系だと思ってた
まぁ　その弟にとっては女系みたいなもんだけどね
It certainly seems that way to his brother.
So, I have to make a trip to the middle school today.
なので　今日僕中学校寄ってかないと
すみません　お先に
Sorry, guys. I'm off.
I'll go with you.
じゃ俺も行くよ　久々に中学覗いてみたいし
I'd like to see my old school again.
ええ　でも
But...
I haven't been there since graduation.
おー　そうやー卒業以来だもんな
はいはい　俺も俺も
All right! I'm coming, too!
I wanna see the middle school you guys attended!
俺もみんなが通ってた中学校見に行く
ねぇねぇ　冬樹君って春ちゃんに似てる？
Hey, does Fuyuki-kun look like Shun-chan?
ああ　似てるかな
Maybe a little.
Really?
マジで？
Th-Thank you for looking after my brother.
いつも兄がお世話になってます
こんなかわゆい子だったらどうしよう
What'll I do if he's that cute?
やべえ　選べねぇよ俺
I could never choose!
You don't have to choose...
選ばなくていいんだよ
Okay! Let's go see Fuyuki-kun!
よーし！それじゃさっそく冬樹君を見に参りますか
Go!
yappari kimi da yo ne
Oh hey, it's you?
honto odoroita yo
You startled me
futari yoku aruita namikidoori
Here we are, on the tree-lined road we walked so often
otona ni naru no wo
I couldn't wait to grow up, and kept you at a distance, didn't I?
matezu ni toozaketeitta no wa watashi datta ne
itsumo
As always,
mainasu ichido no ame ga furu
the icy rain falls
kimi ga kureta namida
comprised of tears you cried for me
sono yasashisa made wakaranakute
That kindness I didn't understand
zutto kono mune wo shimetsuketa
lay heavy on my heart all the time
mainasu ichido no ame ga furu
The icy rain falls
tsumetasugiru namida
comprised of tears unbearably cold
hagurakasu taido ni okotteta keredo
Although I was angry at my evasive personality
---诸神字幕组---
日听 慧慧 低音子  日翻 小月
日校 低音子   总校 AL  时间 葛蔓
jitsu wa sukuwareteita n da ne
you cured me of that, didn't you
弟ができたとき　僕はとてもうれしかった
I was delighted when my brother was born.
A hand smaller than my own.
僕より小さな手
A smile more innocent than my own.
僕よりあどけない笑顔
それが今は…
But now...
Th-Thank you for looking after my—
い　いつも兄がお世話になっ
You're late, Shun-nii.
おせーよ　春兄
もう　これでも急いできたんだから
Jeez. I came as fast as I could.
はい　ノート
Here's your notebook.
あー　外くそ寒い
It's damn cold out here.
Besides, don't I always tell you to turn things in ahead of—
だいたい　提出物は余裕をもって出しなさいっていつも
Yeah, yeah.
はいはいじゃいなくて
Don't give me that. Listen to me properly.
ちゃんとまじめに聞きなさい
Yuuki-kun, how exactly are these two alike?
ちょっと　祐希君
これのどこが似てるって？
Huh? Their hair's kinda similar.
え　似てるじゃん　髪質とか
You idiot!
バカ野郎！
I wasn't asking about such fine details!
俺はそんなピンポイントな話してねんだよ
Who's the one with the weird hair?
つか　そこの変な頭のお前　だれ
I was speaking in more general terms!
What middle school do you go to?
どこ中
I'm not a middle schooler!
中学生じゃねぇ
School of insects?
昆虫
もっとちげえ
No!
Fuyuki!
冬樹
ごめんなさい　千鶴君
I'm sorry, Chizuru-kun.
えっと　この子が弟の冬樹です
Um, this is my younger brother, Fuyuki.
嘘だ
No way.
どういうDNAの神秘が起きた　ここまで似てない子が
What sort of genetic mystery would have to occur to create such different siblings?
ほら冬樹　お友達の橘千鶴君
Come on, Fuyuki.
This is my friend, Tachibana Chizuru-kun.
あぁ　よく話に聞くあの人ね
Oh, the guy you're always talking about.
Oh...
Nice to—
どうもよろし
So tiny!
ちっさ
Fuyuki!
冬樹
They're nothing alike!
やっぱ全然似てねえ
This place hasn't changed a bit.
ちーっとも変わってないな
なに勢揃いで来てんだと思ったら
I was wondering why you brought everyone.
You're all here to see the school, huh?
久々に学校見に来たの
Yes.
冬樹もしばらく見ない間に　また背伸びたんじゃない
You look like you've grown since we saw you last.
あ　わかる
Can you tell? I'm a growing boy, after all...
まぁ　成長期だかんね
Damn. Shorts...
ちぇ　スパッツ
冬樹　マジでお前
You've become a healthy young man
しばらく見ねえ間に健康に育った
since the last time we saw you, Fuyuki.
Huh?
あー　そうそう　超健康なんだよね
Oh, yeah. I'm real healthy.
今度エロ本貸してよ
So lend me some porn sometime.
う　冬樹　何でお前は人前でそういうことを平気で
Fuyuki!
How can you say something like that in public?
But Shun-nii, you don't have any.
だって　春兄全然そういうの持ってねんだもん
You're so boring.
つもんねえ
春兄もほったらかしにしてっと
If you don't use it, you'll lose it.
いい加減腐っちまうぞ
Normally, older brothers have porn somewhere.
ふつーエロ本なんて兄貴が持ってるもんだろうが
Why do you keep saying that in public?
だからなんで人前でそういうことを
まあね
Middle schoolers are at that age.
中学生ってそういう年頃だから
いろんなことに一気に興味が湧いちゃったりね
He's suddenly curious about all sorts of things.
どんまい　どんまい
Don't worry about it.
Wow, he's way ahead of you, Shun.
いや　春の二周先を走ってるって感じだね
春はスタートすらしてねえけどな
Shun hasn't even started yet.
My, my.
好奇心ばかり旺盛な中坊は困っちゃいますな
Curious middle school boys are quite a handful, aren't they?
ほら　なんかわかんないことがあるなら
If there's anything you want to know, you can just ask us.
お兄さんたちに聞いてごらん
なんでも答えてあげるからさ
I'll tell you everything you want to know.
Okay, I heard this from my friend...
あじゃー　これ友達に聞いたんだけどさ
女の子の胸って二の腕の感触に似てるって本当？
Is it true that a girl's boobs feel like your upper arm?
ファーストキスはレモン味かな
I guess you could say that your first kiss tastes like lemons.
いやレモンは聞いてねえから
I'm not asking about lemons.
ちょちょちょっと待って　そうなの
Hey, wait.
Is that true? They feel like upper arms?
二の腕と似てんの
Don't ask me! Just tell him something!
俺に聞くな　なんかそれっぽいこと言っとけ
As his elder, I can't just make something up!
いや　ここは先輩として適当なこと言えないじゃん
レモン味がすでに適当でしょ
Then what was that answer about lemons about?
ていうかさ
Wait a minute. If he heard it from his friend, doesn't that mean his friend has...
友達に聞いたってことは　その友達もう
それ以上は言うな
That's enough!
Oh, come on. None of you know?
んだ　全員まだかよ
大したことねえな　高校生も
High schoolers are nothing special.
あーあ　いろいろ聞こうと思ったのにな
I was going to ask you more questions, too,
because I got a girlfriend recently.
俺最近彼女できたから
なんだなんだ
Come on! What's with this?
ちょっといろいろ知ってて　彼女もいるからって
Just because you know more than us and have a girlfriend...
年下のくせに偉そうにしないでください
You're younger than us,
so please don't act all high and mighty!
敬語になってんぞ
You just said "please."
A crushing defeat.
惨敗
冬樹彼女できたの？
Fuyuki, you got a girlfriend?
お兄ちゃん知らなかった
I didn't know.
Well, yeah.
まあ…な
Damn it! Show us this girlfriend of yours!
ちくしょう　その彼女とやら見せろー
Where is she? Where is she now?
どこだ　いまどこにいる
なんでそこまで見たがんだよ
Why do you want to see her so badly?
Because I want to!
見たいものは見たいんじゃ
How about a picture...
じゃ写メ
A picture will do, right?
写メ入ってから　それでいいだろう
こら　松岡君
Hey, Matsuoka-kun!
Bringing your phone to school again!
また学校に携帯持ってきて
I told you not to do that!
ダメって言ってるでしょう
没収します
I'll be confiscating it.
Hey, wait...
ちょ　待って
ほら見せて見せて
Come on! Show us! Show us the real thing!
Show us, show us.
実物実物
Fine, fine!
あー　もう分かったつの
Is this a dojo?
ここって武道場？
Your girlfriend's in the Kendo Club?
彼女剣道部なのか
Yeah.
そう　いいかお前ら
Listen, you're only gonna look!
見るだけだぞ
Once you get a glimpse of her, get outta here!
ちらっと見たらすぐ帰んだかんな
Okay, okay, okay.
Oh, what's this?
おーー　なんだなんだ　浅羽に松岡
Asaba and Matsuoka, it's good to see you again.
久しぶりじゃねえか　おい
It's nice to see you again.
お久しぶりです
It really is.
本当だよ
引退してから一度も顔出さねんだもんな　お前ら
I haven't seen you guys even once since you left the club.
Sorry.
すみません
Huh?
What?
中学校んとき　悠太と春　剣道部だったんだよ
Yuuta and Shun were both in
the Kendo Club during middle school.
What? Seriously?
へえ　マジで？！
Hey, why don't you give it a go for old times' sake?
そうだ　久々にやってけよ
後輩の指導も兼ねてさ
You can show these kids a thing or two!
Oh, no...
いえ　それは
Right?
Um, I've really forgotten what to do.
あの　本当もう感覚忘れちゃってるんで
Hey, these guys are going to teach you today!
おーい　今日はこの兄ちゃんたちに指導してもらえ
They're your seniors!
お前らの先輩だ
Okay!
はい
かっこいい～
相手の都合聞いてねえ
He's not listening.
A-Amazing!
す　すっげえ
平成のラストサムライ
The last samurai of the 20th century!
悠太　かっこいい
Yuuta, you're so cool.
いや　すごい分
More like scary, with the way he's knocking them down left and right so indifferently.
淡々と切り捌くさまが逆にこえぇんだけど
あれ　松岡
Huh? Matsuoka?
間宮
Mamiya!
What are you doing here?
どうしたの　こんなところで
や　ちょっと　兄貴が久しぶりに剣道部見たいって
Nothing, I just...
My brother said he wanted to see the Kendo Club again.
Oh.
お　お兄さん
Your brother? Oh, right.
そっか　確か剣道部だったって
You did say that he used to be in the Kendo Club.
Mamiya, what are you doing without your protective gear?
間宮こそ　防具もつけずに
I just came back from the bathroom.
あたしはちょっとトイレ行ってて
もしかして彼女さん　こいつの
Are you his girlfriend?
Oh, um...
え　あー　えっと
気をつけなさいよ
You should be careful.
油断してるとあっという間にこのエロ助に食べられ
If you don't watch out, this pervert will eat you...
ってーな　お前
Hey, that hurt!
俺の頭が普段から殴られ慣れてるからよかったものの
You're lucky I'm used to being hit on the head!
うるせー
Shut up!
見るだけつったろうか
I told you to just look!
余計なこと喋んじゃねえよ
Don't say weird things to her!
Oh, I see.
I bet you act all innocent in front of your girlfriend.
さてはお前　彼女の前では淡泊ぶってんの
みなさん
Hey, everyone!
Whether asleep or awake,
松岡冬樹くんは寝ても覚めても頭ん中スケベなことばーっか
Matsuoka Fuyuki's got nothin' but dirty thoughts in...
Matsuoka, that's dangerous!
松岡
危ないよ
You shouldn't swing a sword at people without protective gear on!
防具もつけてない人に竹刀振り回しちゃ
But he's spreading lies about me...
いや　こいつがあることないこと言うから
二の腕
Upper arm...
Matsuoka?
松岡
N-Nothing.
あや　なんでも
こら間宮　さっさと練習戻らんか
Hey, Mamiya! Get back to practice!
Yes, sorry!
あ　はい　すみません
じゃ　また夜電話するね
I'll call you tonight, okay?
Sure.
ぅおい　てめえ　一度ならず二度までも
Hey, you!
That's twice now!
Look at these bumps!
見ろうよ　これたんこぶ
やべえ　携帯
Oh, crap. My phone!
It was confiscated. I've gotta get it back.
没収されてたんだ　取り返さねえと
取り返すってそんな
Get it back?
もともと持ってくんの
It's your fault for bringing—
Mamiya's gonna call me tonight!
夜　間宮から電話くんだよ
没収されてんじゃ電話出れねえじゃん
I can't answer if I don't have it!
If that happens, she might call my house.
そしたらあいつ　家にかけてくるかもしんねえし
もしそんとき　俺風呂に入ってて
If I'm taking a bath at the time,
my parents will answer.
親が電話出て　そんで　あとでさっきの子誰って聞かれてたら
If they ask me who that girl was... What would I tell them?
なんて言えば
お前って意外に
You're surprisingly...
What?
なんだよ
I don't have time for you guys.
つーことだから　お前らにかまってる暇
Hold on, young man!
まぁまぁ　待ちたまえ　少年
そういうことなら
Let us big bros help you out!
お兄さんが一肌脱いであげましょう
Why are you including us?
なに「たち」って
Don't bring me into this.
俺は含まなくていいから
You And I
Oh, crap. There's a whole load of teachers in there.
やっべえ　結構先生いるな
小畑も携帯の近くに居やがるし
And Obata's near my phone.
心配すんな　少年
Don't worry, young man!
当たって砕けても　それもまた青春だ
Trying and failing is a part of youth!
俺たちに明日はない
There's no tomorrow for us!
And they say failure is the root of success.
失敗は成功のもとって言うしね
What I'm most worried about is you guys
assuming we'll fail from the very beginning.
失敗前提で喋ってるお前らが一番心配なんだよ
Put some effort into it.
もっと気合入れろよ
Do you guys really want to do this?
やる気あんのか
You idiot! It's not that easy!
バカ野郎　簡単に言うな
俺の変装がばれるのも時間の問題なんだぜ
It's only a matter of time before they see through my disguise!
俺の学ラン　ジャストサイズじゃねえか
My uniform fits you perfectly!
That's the only thing that's perfect.
そこだけは完璧だよね
What did you say?
何をー
A uniform can't conceal my adult appeal!
学ラン羽織ったぐらいじゃ
俺の大人の色気は隠し切れねえだろう
その辺は大丈夫です
I wouldn't worry about that.
もともと隠さないといけない色気はないので
You don't have any appeal to hide.
えーい　こうなったらやるしかねえ
We'll just have to go for it!
Go forth, warrior! Asaba Yuuki!
行け　先陣　浅羽祐希
It's nice to see you again, Sensei.
先生　お久しぶりです
What?
あら　あらら　浅羽君
Oh, my, Asaba-kun?
What are you doing here?
It's good to see you.
どうしたの　久しぶりじゃない
You've matured quite a bit.
大人っぽくなってまぁ
小畑先生　昔の教え子さんですか
I see.
Obata-sensei, is he one of your former students?
Yes.
そうなのよ
He's a second year high school student now?
今高校二年生だって
You've grown.
背伸びたわね
Damn it.
畜生
Ow!
What are you doing? Hurry—
何してんだよ　早く
Hold on. Give me your phone.
ちょっと待って　お前携帯貸せ
身代わり　没収した携帯がいきなりなくなってたらあやしまれんだろうが
What?
It'll be a decoy!
If the phone she confiscated suddenly disappears, she'll get suspicious!
You're crazy. Why does it have to be mine?
ふざけんなよお前　だからって　何で俺のを
I thought you said you'd help me out!
一肌脱ぐっつっただろうか
I need that help now, you bug!
さっさと脱皮しろっつんだよ
Hey, stop treating me like an insect!
だからテメェはいちいち俺を昆虫に例えんじゃねえよ
Shut up and give me...
つべこべ言ってないでさっさと…
All right, got...
よーしゃ　貰った
No, you don't!
させるか　とりゃっ
My, my.
I-I'm so sorry!
すみません
Pickled plums... Pickled plums...
梅干し　梅干し
H-Hang in there!
し　しっかりしろ
Huh?
って　あれ　俺の携帯は？
Where's my phone?
You mean this?
これのことかな
Oh, thank...
あ　ありがとうござ
学校に携帯持ってきちゃだめだよね
Don't you know that you shouldn't bring your phone to school?
没収されました
He confiscated it.
Moron!
あほー
松岡　さっきちょっと様子変だったな
Matsuoka...
He was acting kind of weird...
どうしたんだろう
I wonder what happened...
や　あのOBの人　超かっこしいんだけど
That graduate guy was so cool!
Jeez! Why are we wearing our gear at a time like this?
あ　もう　こういう時に限って何で防具かな
すごい匂いのに　これ
It stinks.
ね　制服だったら
I think we could've stood a chance in our uniforms.
まだ可能性があったのに
What does that mean?
何よ　可能性って
It's only slightly sprained.
軽く捻っただけだから
湿布で大丈夫だと思うんだけど
It should be fine with just a bandage.
あ　ありがとうございます
Th-Thank you.
Are you all right? It's dangerous to lose your focus.
大丈夫ですか　集中してないと危ないですよ
Yes, I'm sorry.
はい　すみません
Huh? There's no answer.
あれ　出ない
What should I do?
どうしよう
What if Matsuoka thought my protective gear smelled...
もしかして　松岡　あたしとしゃべってる時
防具臭かったとか
It stinks!
臭い
えっと　間宮さん
Um, Mamiya-san?
Yes?
はい
ごめんね　俺そろそろ戻らないとなんだけど
Sorry, but I have to get going.
じゃあ　僕がついててあげますよ
I'll stay with her.
そう　じゃあ　よろしくね
Really? Thanks.
I'm alone with Matsuoka's older brother!
松岡のお兄さんと二人っきり
怱々がないようにしないと
I better not do anything stupid!
Um, Mamiya-san...
あの　間宮さん
Y-Yes?
は　はい
冬樹の兄です
I'm Fuyuki's brother.
いつも　うちの冬樹とその
It seems like... you've been taking good care of my brother lately, so...
すごく仲良くしてくれるみたいで
いえ　そんな　こちらこそ
No, he's been taking care of me.
何かあったら　いつでも言ってくださいね
Let me know if anything happens.
ほら　冬樹　口は悪いし乱暴でしょう
You know how Fuyuki's got such a foul mouth and he's violent?
この間も　うちのレンジが調子悪くて
Our microwave wasn't working recently.
叩けば治るって言って　もっと壊しちゃって
He said hitting it would fix it,
and now it's even more broken.
松岡っぽいです
That sounds like Matsuoka.
そうなんですよね　口が悪くて乱暴で
You're right. He's foul-mouthed and violent,
それなのに　たまに優しかったりするから
but sometimes he's nice and it makes my heart jump...
ドキッとしちゃうって言うか
ああ　いえ　ドキッて言うのは
I mean, out of surprise!
It jumps out of surprise...
びっくりの方で　驚いてドキッの方で
Yes. Fuyuki is kind sometimes.
はい　確かに冬樹　たまに優しいんです
When we were younger and I hurt myself,
子供のころ　僕が怪我をした時
he would try to carry me,
even though he was smaller...
自分の方が小っちゃいのに
おんぶしてくれようとしてくれたり
Hey, don't be so angry.
あー　そんなにプリプリすんなよ
Sorry. We did everything a couple of old men could do.
ごめんね　おじちゃんたち頑張ったんだけど
そうだぞ　俺なんか　自分の携帯犠牲にしてまで
That's right! I even sacrificed my own phone.
What? Your phone was lost in vain.
あ？　お前の携帯なんかただの犬死にだろうが
役立たず
How worthless!
キーッ　お前　春ちゃんの弟じゃなかったら
I'd beat the crap out of you if you weren't Shun-chan's brother!
マジで殴ってっかんな
Okay, okay.
Damn it. Why'd I have to go and grope that old lady teacher?
あーくそ　何が悲しくて
婆ちゃん先生の胸なんか鷲摑みしかきゃなんねんだよ
あれが　二の腕みたいな
It would've been great if her boobs were soft like an upper arm—
やわらかな胸だったら最高なん
M-Mamiya!
間宮
Matsuoka.
松岡
D-Did she hear that?
今の　聞かれた
あれ　二人して何してんの　こんな所で
Wh-What?
What are you two doing here?
あ　えと　私は
Oh, I'm just...
Ow...
あっ　痛
Are you okay?
大丈夫
Yes.
はい
冬樹　間宮さんさっき足が
Fuyuki, Mamiya-san hurt her—
春兄　俺がいない間に　間宮に変なこと吹き込んでないだろうな
Shun-nii, I hope you didn't say anything weird to Mamiya while I was gone.
What?
About porn or upper arms!
だから　エロ本のこととか　二の腕とか
何慌てとんじゃエロ助
What are you worried about, you pervert?
Shut up! I don't wanna hear anything from you!
るせー　お前しゃべんな
あ　防具の匂い
The smell of my armor!
あ　じゃ　あたしはそろそろ練習に
I've gotta get back to practice.
何だ　この匂い
What's that smell?
Mamiya?
間宮　おい　いきなりどうし
Hey, what's wrong with...
あたしに近寄んないで
Get away from me!
Hey, Fuyuki-kun, what's wrong?
おーい　冬樹君　どったの　おーい
Hey.
Shut up! Can't you tell?
うっせえな　見たら分かんだろ　今死んでんだよ
I'm dead!
二の腕つかんたら　すっげー嫌がられた
She got really pissed when I grabbed her upper arm.
あー　もうだめだ
Ah, it's over.
She must've found out that I'm a pervert.
絶対エロいってばれたんだよ
It's fine.
いいよもう
どうせ　おれは地球を救うのはエコよりエロだと思ってる
I'm just a guy who thinks more about raunchy things than recycling things.
I don't care about saving the Earth.
地球に厳しい人間だよ
ほっといてくれ
Just leave me alone.
You shouldn't be so hard on yourself.
いや　そこまで自分を責めんでも
Maybe she hates me.
嫌われたかなぁ
You're right, Fuyuki.
そうだね　冬樹
このままだったら 嫌われちゃうかもしれないのね
She might hate you if you don't do anything.
H-Hey, Shun-chan!
ちょっ　ちょっ　春ちゃん
You're too busy thinking dirty thoughts to even...
だって　冬樹はやらしいこと考えるのに忙しくて
他のことには気回してられないんでしょう
pay attention to anything else.
What do you mean by that?
んだよそれ　俺だってな　四六時中お盛んなわけじゃ
It's not like I think about it all the time—
Then what was that smell?
じゃぁ　さっき何の匂いがしたの
自分のことより
Don't you think there's something...
もっとほかに気づいてあげないといけないことがあるんじゃないの
you should be worrying about more than yourself?
What, what?
何々　どうしたの
What's going on?
Ow...
What am I going to do? I'm so embarrassed.
どうしようどうしよう　恥ずかしい
やっぱりあたし　防具臭かったんだ
My protective gear must've reeked.
He must hate me.
絶対嫌われた
だって　防具臭い彼女なんて聞いたことないし
I've never heard of a girlfriend with stinky gear.
Matsuoka!
松岡
あ　ダメダメ　離れて
No!
No, no, no, no!
Get back! I smell of stinky gear right now!
あたし　今防具臭いから
I knew it! A bandage!
ほら　やっぱり湿布
What?
さっきの匂い　やっぱり　これだったんだな
I knew this was the source of that smell.
つかお前　足どうしたんだよ
Hey, what'd you do to your foot?
ちょっとだけ捻って
Oh, I sprained it a little.
You sprained it? Why did you run, then?
捻った　じゃ　なんで　ばたばた走んだよ
大人しくしてなきゃダメじゃん
You need to rest!
はい　すいません
Oh, yes. Sorry...
You shouldn't practice any more today.
今日もう部活終われ
I'll walk you...
家まで送って…
あ　家まで送るから
I'll walk you home.
No, it's fine!
Huh?
You don't need to take me home.
だって　そんな　家までとか
親に見られて　さっきの子誰って聞かれたら
What will I tell my parents if they ask me who you are?
何っていえば
Tell them I'm your boyfriend.
彼氏って言えばいいじゃん
My phone's been confiscated,
so could you call my house?
あの　俺　今　携帯没収中なので
電話　家の方に
Okay.
はい
Middle school kids are so far ahead these days.
最近の中学生は進んでんなー
This must be what they call a "generation gap".
こう言うのを　ジェネレーションギャップと人は呼ぶのだろうね
呼ばねえよ　三つしか違わねえだろ
No, it's not. We're only three years older than them.
千鶴今日は散々だったね　巻添えで携帯没収されちゃうし
Chizuru, you've had a busy day.
You even ended up having your phone confiscated.
Look on the bright side. Unlike Fuyuki,
Chizuru doesn't have a girlfriend to call him.
まあ　千鶴は冬樹と違って
電話かけてくる彼女がいないのが不幸中の幸いだったけど
いや　それは不幸中の不幸だよ
No, that's actually pretty dark.
Forget it!
ほっとけ　あーもうほんと最悪
Ah, this sucks...
携帯はいつでもゆっくり取りに行けばいいじゃん
You can go get your phone whenever you want.
Shun-chan, where did Fuyuki-kun go wrong?
春ちゃん　冬樹君はいつからあんなすれちゃったの
昔はもっと可愛かったっしょ？
Wasn't he a good kid before?
昔ですか　昔はうーんと　口が悪くて乱暴で
Before? He was always...
foul-mouthed and violent...
Oh come on! That means he hasn't changed a bit!
あー何それ　結局昔から変わってないんじゃん
はい　変わってないんですよ
Yes. He hasn't changed at all.
He's foul-mouthed and violent,
口が悪くて　乱暴で
それなのに　たまに優しかったりするとこも
but sometimes he shows a kind side.
不束者ですが　よろしくお願いします
He may not have much going for him, but please look after him.
Middle School Diary
boku wa nakimushi de kuyashikute dakedo
It pains me to be such a crybaby,
anata ni ima tsutaetai n da
but I want to tell you my feelings right now
tada massugu ni boku wo mitsumeru tsuyokute
There you stand, silently gazing at me
Giving me the chance to answer the strength and tenderness in your eyes
yasashii sono hitomi ni kotaeru tame ni
itsushika miushinatteta ichiban taisetsu na mono mo
you taught me about what I lost sight of
sotto anata ga oshiete kureta
that was most important to me
tashika ni sou omoeru kara
I have no doubts about that
boku wa yowamushi de iya datta dakedo
I hated how weak I was
motto motto tsuyoku naru kara
but I will continue to become stronger
anata no koto wo mamoreru you na boku ni naru kara
I will be someone who could protect you
dakara sukoshi mattete
so wait a little longer for me
The Sunshine Song
Next time: The Sunshine Song.
次回　陽だまりの詩